### **Andrew Alford**

□ andrewalford1@outlook.com □ Github □ LinkedIn

I am a Software Engineer from the UK specialising in both games development (through my degree) and programming for the web (through my own interests). My goals are to constantly be improving my quality of code and to work within industry on new projects with exciting technologies.

#### **Education**

**BSC (HONS) Computer Science with Games Development** Northumbria University Newcastle - Sept 2016 - July 2019

- First Class Degree with Honours
- Graded at 82% with 360 credits
- I received 77% in my dissertation

Other Qualifications A-Levels & GCSEs - Sept 2012 - July 2016

- A-Level Computer Science, mathematics, and Design & Technology
- Nine GSCEs including Mathematics, English, & Science

#### **Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, C#, C++, Java, Python

Libraries & APIS: React, THREE JS, CANNON JS, OpenGL, DirectX

Software & Tools: VS Code, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Overleaf, The Adobe Suite

## **Extra curricular Activity**

Northumbria University Newcastle Student Volunteer- Sept 2016 - July 2019

- Treasurer of the Ouseburn Farm charity society
- Secretary of the Ad-Hoc society
- Community Week captain for 2017/18
- All of these roles involved:
  - Leadership experience
  - Working alongside the students Union and other notable charities
  - o safeguarding and stewardship training

Nissan Third place winner of the Nissan Tech Challenge - April 2018

- A technical and physical challenge held between many Universities from the North East
- The challenge included:
  - Solving technical and coding-oriented puzzles under time
  - Coordinating as a team to work through physical trials such as tree-top obstacle courses and a country wide scavenger hunt

# **Experience**

**Tracerco** | Software Engineer | July 2019 - Present

Northern Football Club | Bar Staff | Jan 2016 - July 2019

### References